Meet the Patels is a romance, comedy, documentary film directed by Ravi Patel.
Finding love is never easy.
For Ravi Patel, a first generation Indian-American, the odds are slim.
His ideal bride is beautiful, smart, funny, family-oriented, kind and—in
keeping with tradition—Indian (though hopefully raised in the US).
Oh, and her last name should be Patel because in
India, Patels usually marry other Patels.
And so at 30, Ravi decides to break up with his American girlfriend (the one who by all accounts is perfect for him except
for her red hair and American name) and embark on a worldwide search for another Patel longing to be loved.
He enlists the help of his matchmaker mother, attends a convention of
Patels living in the US and travels to wedding season in India.
Witty, honest and heartfelt, this comedy explores the
questions with which we all struggle: What is love?
What is happiness?
And how in the world do we go about finding them?
Self, played by Ravi Patel.
Self, played by Geeta Patel.
Self, played by Champa V. Patel.
Self, played by Vasant K. Patel.
Self, played by Audrey Wauchope.
Meet the Patels is a 2014 American romantic comedy documentary film
directed by siblings Geeta Patel and Ravi Patel.
The film explores the expectations surrounding marriage in the Patels'
first-generation Indian immigrant family and in wider American society.
It had its international premiere at Hot Docs in April 2014.
Fox Searchlight acquired remake rights after the documentary won
the Audience Award at the Los Angeles Film Festival.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and emotional.